

- +372 5649 9091
- kairokorgend@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/kairo-kõrgend
- kairokorgend.netlify.app

EDUCATION -

kood/Jõhvi

Software development program 2024 - Present

Estonian Entrepreneurship University of Applied Sciences

Bachelor of Business Management Completed in 2023

Tallinn Polytechnic School

Vocational secondary education IT and telecommunication Completed in 2020

PROJECTS -

Devlink - matching platform

- Full-stack application where developers and recruiters can find one anothersimilar to Tinder, but for the tech industry.
- Developed with React on the front end and Golang on the back end, using JWT for secure authentication.
- Utilized PostgreSQL for data storage, Redis for caching, and WebSockets for real-time connections.

Pathfinder algorithm

- Created an algorithm to find the most efficient paths to move trains from one destination to another.
- Utilized Djikstra, Depth-first search (DFS) and Breadth-first search (BFS).

KAIRO KÕRGEND

SUMMARY

I am an ambitious front-end developer with experience in creating a comprehensive management software solution for managing international clients devices using React and TypeScript. I am among the top 5% of students in the kood/Jõhvi program, demonstrating strong software development and problem-solving skills. Thanks to my financial management experience, I can combine technical development with a strong business sense to build user-friendly, scalable, and cost-effective web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Themo Nordic Oy

2024 - Present

<u>Front-End Developer - (Independent Contractor)</u>

- Independently developed a management software solution for managing international clients devices (8 month project)
- Utilized React + TypeScript, integrated REST APIs, designed UI/UX components, and used Redux for state management.
- Leveraged Azure DevOps for version control and sprint planning, while actively participating in code reviews.

Rasketehnikahooldus (RNE OÜ)

2022 - 2024

Chief Accountant

- Led financial operations as Chief Accountant for a heavy machinery maintenance company.
- Managed full cycle accounting, payroll, and prepared reports for regulatory compliance and executive insights.
- · Conducted cost analyses, ensured budgetary control and identified optimization opportunities.

SKILLS -

Frontend Backend **DevOps & Tools** React Golana Docker Git

- JavaScript Node.js
- TypeScript PostgreSQL
- SQLite Redux
- Azure DevOps
- Postman